Contact

hector@brainx.biz

www.linkedin.com/in/hector-tanfman (LinkedIn) www.brainx.biz/ (Company)

Top Skills

Graphic Design Web Design Proposal Writing

Hector Tan

Entrepreneur & Founder @BrainX (part of Microsoft for Startups Founders Hub) | Startup Nanolearning

Vietnam

Summary

* My startup journey as BrainX's founder:

I'm a Vietnamese entrepreneur by trait. I entered the mobile app business on Google Store and Apple Store from 2017. Then I started a software outsourcing business on Upwork during the pandemic in 2021. This helped me understand how Upwork works.

I hired and worked with remote freelance developers in different countries. It was a good experience working with quality freelance developers who delivered professionalism, satisfaction, peace of mind and revenue to my projects versus not quality developers.

I also worked for 2 software outsourcing companies and 2 startups. By the end of 2021, I had a chance to work remotely with the neurotech startup NeuroGeneces in the US as a CEO assistant.

These personal and professional experiences have led me to found BrainX, a freelance tech talent platform connecting Asia's top tech talents to highly-paying job markets.

Visit website: https://brainx.biz/

For any business matters, message me or email hector@brainx.biz

Skills: startup business | user-centric product design | LinkedIn content marketing

Experience

BrainX

Founder

September 2022 - Present (7 months)

BrainX is a freelance platform for outsourcing your software projects to Asia's vetted tech talents

BrainX is a remote-first Vietnamese startup

NeuroGeneces

Assistant To Chief Executive Officer December 2021 - April 2022 (5 months)

New Mexico, United States

I support CEO & CSO on on business strategy, market research and mobile app design.

NeuroGeneces is a neurotech startup developing a sleep headband using audio stimulation to enhance memory consolidation and brain health at Ultra Sleep (Hz<1).

https://neurogeneces.com/.

BrainX

Founder

February 2021 - April 2022 (1 year 3 months)

I build an idea to improve brain fitness & brain performance, do all the startup work myself (find founders & funding, market research, website design, pitching, business planning, financial planning,...).

One of applicants at Antler 2022.

BrainX is Neurotech startup developing headband to improve your BRAIN FITNESS

FMan Soft

Founder

May 2021 - November 2021 (7 months)

Build professional Website & Mobile App for businesses.

My role was about marketing, sales and working directly with small B2B clients from Australia, Japan, US, Europe.

Upwork channel: https://www.upwork.com/freelancers/~014a7416f6ff3c5421? viewMode=1

https://fmansoft.com/

Appie

Mobile app startups

January 2017 - April 2021 (4 years 4 months)

I programmed and designed Android apps, deal with user's reviews, sell them on Google Play and adjust apps' features to meet user's expectations. I managed my app business via Google Developer Console. I learned to analyze the Console's data and made business-relating decisions from there.

VIoT Group
Machine Learning Developer
June 2018 - March 2020 (1 year 10 months)
Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

VIOT is a smart street light startup

- I developed Face Recognition system with FaceNet for the company's staff check-in.
- I build a Python-based Face Analysis program using Amazon's Face Rekognition. The program can detect age, emotions which is used for Smart Advertising.
- I ran those programs on embedded platform Ndivia.

ExNodes - Excellent Nodes LMT Co. Software Developer 2018 - 2018 (less than a year) Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

*At Exnodes:

- I had chance to learn new programming languages like NodeJS, React JS.
- I helped build a Chatbot for food order and flood report. I firstly used Machine Learning to recognize Coca brand and integrated into Chatbot.
- I used OpenCV to integrate Face Recognition into check-in system.

Apps Cyclone Android Developer 2016 - 2016 (less than a year) Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

*At App Cyclones: I joined an Android team to code social network platform for pet lovers.

Youth Foreign Language English Speaker & Presenter 2015 - 2016 (1 year) Phú Nhuận, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Support the school's students to practice their speaking skill.
- Present various topics in front of a crowd every weekend.

Trường quốc tế Việt Anh English Teaching Assistant 2013 - 2014 (1 year)

Assist foreign teachers in class management, translation.

Education

FPT University

Business Administration and Management, General · (January 2020 - January 2021)

RMIT University

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Machine Learning · (January 2018 - January 2020)